Finding Aid for the Paul A. Marquardt Music for Silent Films PASC-M.0004
UCLA Library Special Collections
Paul A. Marquardt music for silent films
1925-1943
UCLA Library Special Collections
Marquardt, Paul (Composer)
PASC-M.0004
4.4 Linear Feet (6 flat boxes and 2 oversize flat boxes)
This collection contains the manuscript and published scores of film composer Paul A. Marquardt.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Mrs. Frank Dellestritto, 1975.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9922213273606533
Biography/History
Paul Marquardt was born on 13 January 1889 in Rudolstadt, Thuringia, Germany as Paul Alfred Marquardt. Over the course of his career as a film music composer, he worked on some of MGM's most famous films, such as The Wizard of Oz (1939), A Day at the Races (1937) and Rio Rita (1942). He died on October 30, 1960 in Los Angeles, California, USA.
Scope and Content
This collection largely contains manuscripts and manuscript reproductions for various compositions, either composed or arranged by Marquardt. Also included are several marches, an opera, and 67 pieces of silent film music published by the Music Buyers Corporation.
Organization and Arrangement
This collection has been arranged into the following series:
Series 1. Manuscripts
Series 2. Published scores
Silent film music -- Scores.; Music -- Manuscripts.
- Manuscripts, 1928-1943
  Scope and Content
  This series contains manuscripts and manuscript reproductions of various compositions.
  - Archibald Douglas (Ballade), Op. 138. Adaptation of ballad by Theodor Fontane; composed by Carl Loewe, arranged by P. A. Marquardt. Orchestral score, 1941 March 12 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Concertino (12th Concerto) for Violin and Orchestra. Composed by Louis Spohr, new edition by P.A. Marquardt. Orchestral score, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - March (D minor). Orchestral score, 1929 February 18 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - March (F major). Orchestral score and parts, 1928 September (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - March (G major). Orchestral parts, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Melodies of Josef Strauss: Fantasia for Piano and Orchestra. Orchestral parts, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - A Merry Overture. Orchestral score, draft copy, 1942 December 4 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - A Merry Overture. Orchestral score, final copy, 1942-1943 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - A Merry Overture. Piano score, circa 1942 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Opera (Scene 1).Orchestral score, 1938 March 25 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Opera (Scene 2).Orchestral score, 1938 April 12 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Opera (Scene 1). String parts, circa 1938 (Box 6, Folder 4-5)
  - Ramasan: Oriental Suite (Part I). String parts, 1930 (Box 4)
  - Ramasan: Oriental Suite (Part I). Woodwind and brass parts, 1930 (Box 5)
  - Ramasan: Oriental Suite (Part I). Percussion parts, 1930 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Ramasan: Oriental Suite (Part I). Orchestral score, 1930 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Ramasan: Oriental Suite (Parts II and III). Orchestral score, 1930 June 16 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Regimenstag: Marsch. Parts for 1st clarinet, tuba, and drums (ozalid copy), undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Rondeau Brillant. Orchestral parts, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Serenade for Five Wood Instruments. Conductor's score and parts, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Sonata in C minor (composed by H.I.F. Biber, arranged by P. A. Marquardt). Orchestral score, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Sonata in C minor (composed by H. I. F. Biber, arranged by P. A. Marquardt). Violin parts, undated (Box 7)
  - Sonata in C minor (composed by H. I. F. Biber, arranged by P. A. Marquardt). Viola, cello, and bass parts, undated (Box 8, Folder 1-3)
  - Sonata in C minor (composed by H. I. F. Biber, arranged by P. A. Marquardt). Orchestral parts, undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - The Unknown Soldier: Legend for Baritone, Male Chorus and Orchestra. Vocal scores, 1941 September 2 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Untitled composition. Orchestral score, 1941 March 29 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Untitled fragment, undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Published scores, 1925-1928
  This series contains published sheet music. The scores all have the same format and were largely printed by one publisher, likely sequentially. Sheets have been numbered by Marquardt, and this numbering has been retained, though it does not correspond to a strictly chronological arrangement.
  - 1. The Enchanted Castle (Poeme Mysterieuse), 1926 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 2. Scherzo Silhouette, 1928 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 3. Ardent Affection (A Passionate Episode), 1928 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 4. Witty Moments (Humoresque), 1928 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 5. Vision Orientale, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 6. A Night in the Orient (Dance of the Harem), 1927 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 7. A Desert Dance (Dramatic Oriental Dance). 2 copies, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 8. Fi-Ya-Di (Oriental Dance), 1925 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 9. A Halloween Ride (Characteristic Sketch), 1928 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 10. The Midnight Parade (A Mysterious Episode), 1927 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 11. The Devil's Elixir (A Mysterious Patrol), 1927 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 12. The Wooden Soldier's Tournament, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 13. Happy Moods (Intermezzo), 1927 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 14. The Hermit's Dream (Pastorale Romantique), 1928 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 15. Love's Response (Romance), 1928 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 16. Love's Emotion (Andante Appassionato), 1928 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 17. To My Star (Serenade Romantique), 1928 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 18. Wild Flowers (Intermezzo), 1928 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 19. Woodland Frolics (Rondeau), 1928 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 20. Wedding Dreams (A Love Story), 1928 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 21. Morning Dew (An Outdoor Episode), 1927 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 22. The Season's Greetings (Serenade), 1927 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 23. Spring Fancies (Intermezzo), 1925 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 24. Dreamy Moments (Serenade Amorous), 1925 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 25. Pearls of My Soul (Reverie Religieuse), 1925 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 26. Romance of Autumn (Poeme Elegiac), 1925 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 27. Alone at Night (Meditation), 1925 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 28. Moonlight Dreams (Nocturne), 1926 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 29. Star Night (Nocturne), 1925 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 30. Hidden Love (An Old Love Song), 1927 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 31. The Lure of Crimson (Tragic Sonata), 1925 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 32. Moonlight in Naples (Barcarolle), 1925 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 33. Springtime of Life (Serenade), 1925 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 34. Reproche d'Amour (Entr' Acte), 1925 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 35. Dance of the Sylphes (Valse de Ballet). Score missing, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 36. A Regal Episode: The King's Entrance (March Pomposo), 1927 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 37. A Smile- A Kiss (Ballad), 1928 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 38. Incidental Symphonies: Stormy Conflict, 1925 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 39. Incidental Symphonies: The Villain's Den, 1925 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 40. Incidental Symphonies: Furious Enemies, 1925 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 41. Incidental Symphonies: The Coaching Party, 1928 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 42. Incidental Symphonies: Threatening Sea, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 43. Symphonic Color Classics No. 5: A Twentieth Century Romance, 1925 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 44. Symphonic Color Classics No. 6: A Sex Drama, 1926 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 45. Symphonic Color Classics No. 9: A Gypsy Romance, 1928 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 46. Franco- Espano Suite (Spanish Love Theme), 1927 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 47. Miracle Scene (From Offenbach's Opera, "The Tales of Hoffmann". arranged by P.A. Marquardt), 1928 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 48. Symphonic Color Classics No.1: In Autumn, 1925 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 49. Symphonic Incidentals No. 1: Damnation, 1926 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 50. Symphonic Incidentals No. 2: Threatening Winds, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 51. Symphonic Incidentals No. 3: The Captive's Lament, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 52. Symphonic Incidentals No. 4: Chasing Phantoms, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 53. Symphonic Incidentals No. 5: Allegro Scherzo or Dramatic Tarantelle, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 54. Symphonic Incidentals No. 6: Ominous Moments, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 55. Symphonic Incidentals No. 7: Tragic Pathos, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 56. Symphonic Incidentals No. 8: Nautical Allegro, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 57. Symphonic Incidentals No. 9: Overture Allegro Suspense, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 58. Symphonic Incidentals No. 10: Hurried Overture Allegro, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 59. Symphonic Incidentals No. 11: A Tragedy, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 60. Symphonic Incidentals No. 12: Abomination, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 61. Symphonic Incidentals No. 13: Fatalistic, 1928 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 62. Symphonic Incidentals No. 14: Sinister Drama, 1928 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 63. Symphonic Incidentals No. 15: Scherzo Sinister, 1928 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 64. Symphonic Incidentals No. 16: Regal Allegro Non Troppo, 1928 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 65. Symphonic Incidentals No. 17: Sinister Pathos, 1928 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 66. Symphonic Incidentals No. 18: Allegro Tension, 1928 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 67. Symphonic Incidentals No. 19: The Third Degree, 1928 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Fragment of book containing sonatas by various composers, undated (Box 8, Folder 8)